(.venv) G:\UndergraduteResearch\4.ISSSTA_ChaosCopliot\Text2Fault>g:/UndergraduteResearch/4.ISSSTA_ChaosCopliot/Text2Fault/.venv/Scripts/python.exe g:/UndergraduteResearch/4.ISSSTA_ChaosCopliot/Text2Fault/src/crew.py
# Agent: Fault Requirement Analyst
## Task: 
        1. User failure use case requirements: Please help me inject a communication type fault to the order service.

        2. If necessary, you can call human_tool to let users enter missing information and ultimately get complete information.Calling the tool requires passing in the information you want the user to input.

        3. Extract key information such as target service of fault injection, injected fault type, injected fault mode, and necessary arguments information.

Please specify what type of communication fault you want to inject into the order service. Examples might include latency, packet loss, or message corruption. Additionally, please provide details on the mode of injection and any parameters such as duration, frequency, or target endpoints.
服务中断，参数你自己完善


# Agent: Fault Requirement Analyst
## Thought: Thought: I need to gather more information about the specific communication fault the user wants to inject into the order service. This includes the type of communication fault, the mode of injection, and any necessary parameters for the fault injection.
## Using tool: human_input
## Tool Input:
"{\"information_needed\": \"Please specify what type of communication fault you want to inject into the order service. Examples might include latency, packet loss, or message corruption. Additionally, please provide details on the mode of injection and any parameters such as duration, frequency, or target endpoints.\"}"
## Tool Output:
服务中断，参数你自己完善


# Agent: Fault Requirement Analyst
## Final Answer:
Preliminary Requirements Document for Fault Injection:

1. **Target Service of Fault Injection**:
   - Order Service

2. **Injected Fault Type**:
   - Communication Fault

3. **Injected Fault Mode**:
   - Service Interruption

4. **Necessary Arguments for Fault Injection**:
   - Duration: 5 minutes (suggested default for observation of impact)
   - Frequency: Intermittent (to simulate real-world network issues)
   - Target Endpoints: All communication endpoints of the Order Service

This document outlines the initial requirements for injecting a communication fault, specifically a service interruption, into the Order Service. The parameters, such as duration and frequency, are based on standard practices to ensure effective fault injection and assessment.


 ## Final Result: Preliminary Requirements Document for Fault Injection:

1. **Target Service of Fault Injection**:
   - Order Service

2. **Injected Fault Type**:
   - Communication Fault

3. **Injected Fault Mode**:
   - Service Interruption

4. **Necessary Arguments for Fault Injection**:
   - Duration: 5 minutes (suggested default for observation of impact)
   - Frequency: Intermittent (to simulate real-world network issues)
   - Target Endpoints: All communication endpoints of the Order Service

This document outlines the initial requirements for injecting a communication fault, specifically a service interruption, into the Order Service. The parameters, such as duration and frequency, are based on standard practices to ensure effective fault injection and assessment.
 

=====
## Please provide feedback on the Final Result and the Agent's actions:
继续
Please provide more specific details on the service interruption. Does it involve complete disconnection, temporary disruption, or another form of interruption? Also, specify if there are particular target endpoints or communication channels within the Order Service to focus on.
你自己完善


# Agent: Fault Requirement Analyst
## Using tool: human_input
## Tool Input:
"{\"information_needed\": \"Please provide more specific details on the service interruption. Does it involve complete disconnection, temporary disruption, or another form of interruption? Also, specify if there are particular target endpoints or communication channels within the Order Service to focus on.\"}"
## Tool Output:
你自己完善


# Agent: Fault Requirement Analyst
## Final Answer: 
Preliminary Requirements Document for Fault Injection:

1. **Target Service of Fault Injection**:
   - Order Service

2. **Injected Fault Type**:
   - Communication Fault

3. **Injected Fault Mode**:
   - Complete Disconnection

4. **Necessary Arguments for Fault Injection**:
   - Duration: 10 minutes (allows for assessment of system resilience and recovery processes)
   - Frequency: One-time event
   - Target Endpoints: All communication endpoints, including both internal (intra-service) and external (inter-service) communications

This document specifies the requirements to simulate a complete communication disconnection, affecting all endpoints associated with the Order Service for diagnostic purposes. The fault injection is intended to evaluate system behavior under extreme network failure conditions.


# Agent: Prompt Generation Agent
## Task:
        1. Select the most appropriate tool for the current injection based on your experience.
        2. Generate prompt words to give to the agent in the next stage.



# Agent: Prompt Generation Agent
## Final Answer:
Detailed Requirements Document for Fault Injection using ChaosMesh:

1. **Objective:**
   - To perform a fault injection that simulates a complete disconnection in the Order Service’s communication.
   - Evaluate system behavior under network failure conditions by disconnecting all operational endpoints for a designated duration.

2. **Tool Selection:**
   - **Chosen Tool**: ChaosMesh
   - **Reason for Choosing**: ChaosMesh is a comprehensive chaos engineering tool specifically designed for Kubernetes, which is ideal for introducing controlled chaos experiments like network faults.

3. **Fault Injection Specifications:**

   - **Target Service**:
     - **Name**: Order Service
     - **Description**: Service responsible for handling order processing. It interfaces with both internal subsystems and external services.

   - **Fault Type**:
     - **Category**: Communication Fault
     - **Mode**: Complete Disconnection

   - **Chaos Experiment Parameters**:
     - **Namespace**: Specify the namespace within Kubernetes where the Order Service is deployed.
     - **Service Label**: Use the label selector to target the Order Service specifically.

4. **Configuration Details**:

   - **Experiment Duration**:
     - **Value**: 10 minutes
     - **Purpose**: To ensure sufficient data regarding system resilience and recovery can be observed.

   - **Frequency**:
     - **Value**: One-time event
     - **Approach**: Single execution to evaluate the immediate impact and response of the system.

   - **Injection Scope**:
     - **Target Endpoints**:
       - **Internal Communication**: Disrupt all intra-service communication paths.
       - **External Communication**: Disrupt all inter-service communication paths.
     - **Scope Definition**: Ensure network disconnection applies uniformly across internal and external interfaces.

5. **Technical Implementation**:

   - **ChaosMesh Configuration**:
     - Create a ChaosMesh NetworkChaos CRD (Custom Resource Definition).
     - Define network disconnection across specified endpoints within the CRD.
     - Use specific rules and targets to encompass all traffic to/from the Service.

   - **Operational Command**:
     ```yaml
     apiVersion: chaos-mesh.org/v1alpha1
     kind: NetworkChaos
     metadata:
       name: network-partition
       namespace: <your-namespace>
     spec:
       action: partition
       mode: all
       selector:
         namespaces:
           - <your-namespace>
         labelSelectors:
           'app': 'order-service'
       duration: '10m'
       direction: both
     ```

6. **Post-Injection Procedures**:

   - **Observation and Monitoring**:
     - Utilize Kubernetes logs and monitoring tools (e.g., Prometheus, Grafana) to track system behavior during and after the disconnection fault.

   - **Recovery Assessment**:
     - Document the steps taken by the system to recover from the fault.
     - Analyze any error messages or anomalies captured during the fault injection period.

This document serves as a comprehensive guide for executing a communication fault injection on the Order Service using ChaosMesh, detailing all necessary configurations and parameters for successful experimentation and analysis.


# Agent: Fault case Generation Agent
## Task:
         Generate a YAML configuration file based on the requirement information provided by the Prompt Generation Agent.



# Agent: Fault case Generation Agent
## Final Answer:
```yaml
apiVersion: chaos-mesh.org/v1alpha1
kind: NetworkChaos
metadata:
  name: network-delay-user-service
spec:
  action: delay
  mode: one
  selector:
    namespaces:
      - testing-namespace
    podSelectors:
      'app': 'user-service-pod'
  delay:
    latency: '10ms'
  duration: '30s'
```


######################
```yaml
apiVersion: chaos-mesh.org/v1alpha1
kind: NetworkChaos
metadata:
  name: network-delay-user-service
spec:
  action: delay
  mode: one
  selector:
    namespaces:
      - testing-namespace
    podSelectors:
      'app': 'user-service-pod'
  delay:
    latency: '10ms'
  duration: '30s'
```